SONIKA S

sonikasnk09@gmail.com | (+1) 937-794-3865 | Portfolio | LinkedIn | Toledo, Ohio |

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Strategic Marketing Analyst with 3+ years of experience translating complex marketing data into strategic decision-making and innovations, identifying technology trends, and visualizing and presenting data findings. Skilled in applying technical acumen to evaluate and solve client and business problems logically. Able to improve productivity by automating business processes and analyzing data to produce key business insights.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Modern Builders Supply (Toledo, OH) – SEO Specialist & Analyst (1 Year)

08/2024 - Current

- Increased organic website traffic on the <u>e-commerce site</u> by **49% YoY**, contributing to a **79.9% revenue growth** by launching a website enhancement plan.
- Reduced customer churn by 12% by developing Excel and Power BI dashboards for churn analysis and customer feedback trends, enabling data-driven retention strategies aligned with business goals.
- Used Prisync for competitive pricing and positioning, boosting sales at profitable margins.
- Used SPSS to analyze sales data and performed predictive modeling to forecast demand and guide strategic decisions in promotions and inventory management.
- Analyzed marketing KPI data to identify high-ROI channels, leading to optimized budget allocation and improved campaign performance.
- Led a team to improve user experience, redesigning the website interface, resulting in a 38% engagement and a 40% reduction in cart abandonment rate

Lohre and Associates (Cincinnati, OH) - Marketing Analyst Intern (6 Months)

03/2024 - 08/2024

- Created engaging Social Media content for clients, improving traffic by 7000+ visitors
- Built automated email workflows in HubSpot, optimizing sequences and triggers to boost open rates by 12.37%.
- Tracked digital marketing KPIs and ran predictive statistical analysis using SPSS to allocate marketing budget in the right direction
- Launched and managed paid search and display campaigns on Google, Bing, and Google Shopping, achieving an
 increase in ROI.
- Participated in regular client meetings to present campaign performance, gather feedback, and acquire marketing goals.

Bulletin Boards (New Delhi, India) - Digital Marketing Specialist (2 Years)

02/2020 - 03/2022

- Created real-time dashboards and performance reports using Google Looker Studio for bi-weekly client presentations.
- Managed and monitored cost-per-click (CPC), conversion rates, and ROAS to ensure campaign profitability.
- Conducted A/B and multivariate testing on landing pages, improving conversion rates by up to 22%.
- Implemented remarketing campaigns and dynamic product ads, improving retention and lowering customer acquisition cost (CAC).
- Collaborated with design and copy teams to produce high-impact ad creatives aligned with brand voice and audience
 preferences.
- Utilized audience segmentation and geo-targeting to tailor campaigns to demographics, devices, and user behavior.

EDUCATION

Wright State University (Dayton, OH)

Master of Science in Business Analytics, GPA- 3.6

08/2022 - 07/2024

07/2017-05/2020

Delhi University, Kalindi College (India) Bachelor of Science in Life Sciences, GPA- 3

PROJECTS

- **SEO API Integration** Automated SEO performance tracking by integrating Google Search Console API with internal databases, enabling real-time visibility into keyword and page performance.
- **Repeat Customer Analysis** Used SQL to create a report identifying repeat buyers' behavioral patterns on an ecommerce platform, informing the PPC specialist to target them with loyalty and retention strategies.
- Data Analysis of E-commerce website Analyzed Kaggle e-commerce data using regression, decision trees, and k-means clustering. Used SPSS and Python for predictive modeling and Google Analytics metrics to optimize conversion rates and forecast revenue. Improved data quality by 10% via mean imputation and predictive forecasting by 20%

SKILLS & TOOLS

Category	Skills	Rating	Category	Skills	Rating
Data Analysis	Data Cleaning	9	Data Tools	SQL, Python	8.5
	Data Manipulation	9		IBM SPSS, Rapid Miner	7
	Data Visualization	8		Excel, Pivot Table, VLOOKUP	8
	Data Mining	8.5		Google Sheets	8
	Data Visualization	8.5		Tableau, Power BI, Visio	8
	Text Data Analysis	7			
	Classification/ Clustering	8	Marketing	SEO, SEM, Social Media Marketing	8.5
				Keyword Research, Backlinks	9
Google	Google Search Console	9		SEMrush, Ahrefs, SERanking	8.5
	Google Analytics	9.5		Screaming Frog	8.5
	Google Merchant Center	8.5		Email Marketing	9
	Google Ads, Bing Ads	8.5		Marketing Automation	9
				Content Creation, Design	8.5
				Wordpress/ Github/ HubSpot	8
				HTML, CSS, Category Design	8
Other Skills	Troubleshooting	9.5			
	Impact Analysis	8.5	Collaboration	Verbal/Written Communication	8.5
	Adapting to New Technologies	8		Team Collaboration	10
	Root cause analysis (RCA)	8		Agile, Scrum, Notion, Slack, Flock	9
	Problem Solving	6		Ability to work independently	10
	SAP S4HANA / ERP / CRM	7			